Do you give a defined trial period uh
for lifestyle changes before adding
medication for the younger guys?
>> Yeah, I really hate to relegate a young
man. And again, the word young is
subjective, right? Let's let's call it
early to mid 20s, even late 20s, young
man, but specifically I get a lot of
guys for some reason between 20 and 25
that come in. And you know, it's not a
bad thing. I don't dislike seeing them
come in for an assessment. I do dislike
seeing them come in as a transfer
patient already on testosterone because
I feel a lot of them are misdiagnosed
because the sign of low testosterone
does not necessarily mean that they
belong on testosterone therapy at 22 or
23 years old. When they come in
suppressed on therapy from another
clinic and they want us to take over
care and we often do. Um it it it pains
me to see this because you're relegating
a young man who may not have needed this
treatment at this point to a life
lifetime of treatment um before you gave
him a fair chance to really optimize his
body naturally and fully figure out what
was wrong and maybe just make a couple
of tweaks to to improve his health. But
when we get a new fresh guy and we come
in and we do the full gamut of
assessment from luteinizing hormone to
SHBG to sleep patterns etc. I have no
complaints about that whatsoever because
it doesn't mean that just because you
did an intake and did a consultation in
labs that we're going to place you on
testosterone. In fact, I'd say that more
than 50% of the guys that come to us
under the age of 25 end up leaving my
office, not prescribed testosterone, but
they walk away with knowledge and
information on what they could and
should do to enhance their life and then
maybe save another decade before they do
come back in and require any sort of
intervention. So, I would not rush to
put a young man on testosterone. I hate
to see it. Some do need it, some truly
need it, but I hate to see it because um
you know, every every couple years we
notice that the generational gap between
men on treatment and men who need
treatment starts to go down and down and
down and now now they're they're really
young, right? So, I don't like seeing
guys in in their 20s on TRT, but very
few actually need it. Most just kind of
want it and just play along. But I I
really try to not prescribe it to
younger men unless it's it's really
really needed.